**(C)** 

+92 313 0260405



hamza.prolink@gmail.com



/muhammad-hamza-ned



Karachi, Pakistan

# **PROFILE SUMMARY**

I am a self-motivated and hardworking computer science undergraduate student with broad skills and experience in web development. I am a fast learner and passionate about learning new technologies in front-end and back-end web development.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Computer Science & Information Technology | 2020 - Ongoing

NED University of Engineering & Technology

Present CGPA: 3.82

### **CORE STRENGTHS**

Technical Skills:

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript React.js

Next.js Firebase MongoDB Redis

Bootstrap5 MUI Tailwind

Professional Skills:

Team Leadership Problem Solving

Effective Communication Adaptability

Attention to Detail Creativity

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Secured 1st position and a Rs 50k cash prize in WebKoderz'23 Competition by leading team 'Darkhorses' to develop an innovative MERN Stack Scholarship Portal with Al-based Sentiment Analysis and OCR functionalities.

Recognized for streamlining the application process, showcasing dedication, teamwork, and technological excellence.

# **CERTIFICATES**

NodeJS - The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL, Deno) (03/2023)

Maximilian Schwarzmüller on Udemy

React - The Complete Guide (07/2022)

Maximilian Schwarzmüller on Udemy

Interactivity with JavaScript (12/2021)

University of Michigan on Coursera

Introduction to HTML5 (09/2021)

University of Michigan on Coursera

Introduction to CSS3 (10/2021)
University of Michigan on Coursera

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Jr. MERN Stack Developer

Tassaract - Sep 2023 - Present

- Proficient in utilizing React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, and Firebase for web application development.
- · Completed two trading-related projects and two Next.js projects concurrently.
- · Demonstrated ability to manage multiple projects simultaneously.
- · Ensured regular updates and delivered high-quality results across all projects.

### MERN Stack Developer – Internship

Esolace Tech - Jan 2023 - Aug 2023

- Contributed significantly to the development of a dynamic Grocery Management System during a 3month internship at Esolace Tech.
- · Utilized React.js and Redux to create a feature-rich frontend.
- · Experience enhanced technical skills, teamwork, and problem-solving abilities.
- · Appreciative of mentorship and growth opportunities provided by Esolace Tech.

#### **MERN Stack Developer – Internship**

Bytewise Limited - Mar 2023 - June 2023

- Engaged in a dynamic 3-month remote internship at Bytewise Limited, undertaking diverse projects.
- · Developed various applications, from small Todo apps to a full-stack scholarship portal.
- Utilized technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and more.
- · Contributed to the backend of Bytewise's internship management Android app.
- Enhanced technical proficiency and gained insights into real-world application development.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### PEB.AI:

Developed peb.ai, a SaaS website enabling Al-generated Shorts. Built with Next.js 14, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS. Integrated Stripe for secure subscriptions. Deployed on Vercel with Cloudflare. Utilized Flask server deployed on Google VM and Cloud Functions, employing stable diffusion and whisper for short generation.

Website: https://www.peb.ai

### NED Scholarship Portal:

**Backend Includes:** Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, REST API, JWT, Multer, Sendsgrid Email, Input validation, etc.

**Frontend Includes:** React.js, Redux Store, Custom Hooks, Toastify Notifications, Input validation, Fetch API, MUI, etc.

**Website:** <a href="https://ned-scholarship-portal.vercel.app/">https://ned-scholarship-portal.vercel.app/</a>

# FOOD KING:

A fast-food restaurant where users can authenticate via phone number or Google account. Upon authentication, users gain access to their profile, where they can add personal information, addresses, and view past orders and favorite items. It Utilizes Redux store, Redux Toolkit, custom UseInput hook for form validation, Firebase Database, Firebase Authentication, React Bootstrap, react icons, React Toastify for animated notifications, loading UI.

Website: https://fk-nu.vercel.app/

#### **PORTFOLIO:**

Developed a personal portfolio website to highlight expertise in web development. Utilizes Custom Hooks, React Transition Group for animations, Formspree for form validation and email responses, React Visibility Sensor for dynamic content, Type Writer Effect for text animations, Material UI for design elements, Animated Cursor for interactive UX, Circular and Linear Progress Bars for visual representation, and Custom Carousel for dynamic content display.

**Website:** https://portfolio-website-m-hamza-aslam.vercel.app/\_